Mark C. McFadden

818 Scott Street

Covington, KY 41011

Phone: 859-750-1953

http://www.markmcfadden.net

Blog: https://m2.fyi

E-Mail: m2web@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/m2web/

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Over thirty years' experience in the Information Technologies field specializing in Internet Technologies, Network Administration, .Net and J2EE application design and development. I have designed and implemented several Internet based systems ranging from static "brochure ware" sites to dynamic e-commerce solutions. Finally, I have spoken regularly before teams and corporate gatherings educating on various topics and technologies as well as teach at a local University.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML/XHTML/CSS
- C#/.Net Development
- Python
- MVC ASP.Net & .Net Core
- Agile Development Methodologies
- IBM API Connect

- Ruby and Ruby on Rails 3.x
- Bash/PowerShell
- PHP
- Java 1.4 & 1.5 with Struts and Ant
- JavaScript Development & Frameworks
- Elastic Search/Logstash/Kibana Stack

EDUCATION

Major: Business Informatics

School: Northern Kentucky University

Awarded: Master's in Business Informatics Outstanding Student 2009-2010

Degree: Master of Science in Business Informatics- 3.86 GPA Certificate: Graduate Certificate in Enterprise Resource Planning

Completion Date: 12/2009

Major: Networking & Distributed Systems School: Columbus State Community College

Degree/Certificate: Certified Novell Administrator (CNA) - 3.X

Completion Date: 03/1997

Major: Education
School: Ohio University

Degree/Certificate: Bachelor of Science-Summa Cum Laude

Completion Date: 11/1993

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Employer: Western & Southern Financial Group

Location: Cincinnati, OH
Title: Programmer Consultant
Duration: 03/2013 – Present

- Setup, Administered, and Developed Enterprise Gateway APIs
- Developed .Net MVC Web App for On Demand Correspondence
- Developed Java Based Solutions for a New Business Data
- Utilized Websphere Application Server with a DB2 Database
- Constructed Reports from Java to work with a Batch Control Interface API
- Created both Windows Services and Web Services for Service Oriented Architecture
- Utilized Automated Testing Applications such as JUnit for Test Driven Development
- Developed and Presented Demonstrations for New Software Frameworks

Employer: Northern Kentucky University

Location: Highland Heights, KY

Title: Part Time Faculty *Duration: 08/2015 - 5/2023*

• Taught college students Advanced Line of Business Application Programming and Introduction to Database Courses

- Instructor in the Graduate Level Information Technology Governance Course
- GitHub Campus Advisor

Employer: ICES Limited

Location: Air Force Institute of Technology, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio

Title: Web Administrator *Duration: 08/1999 – 11/2000*

- Setup and Administered Four Dell Power Edge 6300 And 6400 Web Servers
- Setup and Administered Internet Information Server 4 And 5 Servers
- Create Active Server Page Web Applications with VB Script, Javascript, And Database Connectivity
- Design and Execution ff MS Access And SQL Server Databases
- Setup and Administered Microsoft Proxy Server
- Supported and Managed Fifteen Web Authors for More Than Twenty Different Web Sites

Employer: PIC 17 Workforce Board

Location: Circleville, Ohio

Title: Systems Administration/Web Developer

Duration: 05/1995 – 08/1999

- Administered Citrix Winframe 1.7 Server with A Custom SQL Server 6.5 Application
- Designed and Provided Training on Various Software Tools and Web Page Creation
- Setup and Administered Linux Red Hat 6 File Server Within A NT 4 Environment
- Created Custom Built Web Based Database Application and Related Manuals and Windows Based Help Files
- Planned, Deployed, And Evaluated Network Hardware and Software Solutions for the Various Partner Agencies
- Supported End Users with Hardware and Software Needs and Problems
- Chaired and Facilitated an Inter-agency Electronic Connectivity Project Consisting of Twenty Separate Agencies

Employer: Great Oaks Institute of Technology

Location: Washington CH, Ohio

Title: Adult Education Computer Instructor (Part Time)

Duration: 09/1997 - 08/1999

- Taught adult students basic computer applications and use of Microsoft Office 95 and 97 Suite Applications
- Taught students in Internet Usage of Web Browsers, E-mail Clients, and News Group Readers

Employer: Great Oaks Institute of Technology (Oak Web Community Internet)

Location: Washington CH, Ohio

Title: System Administrator/Webmaster (Volunteer)

Duration: 08/1995 - 09/1997

- Created and managed Web site on Sun Spare V System
- Monitored and maintained Unix BSD system activity
- Conducted public presentations for Community Network and Internet promotion
- Instructed on Internet use and Web Page creation with JavaScript and HTML